$GeneralSettings	General Settings
$DisplaySettings	Display and Notifications
$Needs	Needs Settings
$SkillTree	Survival Skill Tree
$Help	Help
$Disabled	Disabled
$AnimOptions	Animation Options
$GameplayOptions	Gameplay Options
$Enabled	Enabled
$Vertical	Vertical
$Horizontal	Horizontal
$Alpha	Alpha Based
$Color	Color Based
$AlphaColor	Alpha/Color based
$Top_Left	Top Left
$Top_Right	Top Right
$Bottom_Left	Bottom Left
$Bottom_Right	Bottom Right
$Hunger_Thirst	Hunger and Thirst
$FrostfallMenu	Use Frostfall MCM.
$Hunger	Hunger
$Thirst	Thirst
$Fatigue	Fatigue
$Fatigue_Thirst	Fatigue and Thirst
$Mortal	Mortal (All Needs)
$UpdatingToVersion	: Updating script to version 
$SunHelmSurvival	SunHelm Survival
$ToggleFT	Disable Fast Travel
$PlayEatDrinkAnims	Play Eating/Drinking Animations
$PlayRefillAnims	Play Refilling Animations
$ToggleCannibal	Toggle Cannibalism
$ToggleRaw	Toggle Raw Meat Damage
$ToggleCW	Toggle Carry Weight Penalty
$WerewolfOptions	Werewolf Options
$GeneralOptions	General Options
$VampireOptions	Vampire Options
$WereFills	Werewolf Feed Fills:
$WerewolfFatigue	Werewolf Fatigue
$WerewolfPause	Werewolf Pause Needs
$VampireNeeds	Vampire Needs
$SlowerThirst	Slower Thirst
$DisplayOptions	Display Options
$WidgetOptions	Widget Options
$WidgetLocation	Widget Location
$Notifications	Notifications
$DispMsgNotifs	Display Message Notifications
$SoundNotifs	Sounds notifications
$ToggleWidget	Toggle Widget
$WidgetOrient	Widget Orientation
$WidgDisType	Widget Display Type
$PresetLoc	Preset Location
$WidgXOff	Widget X offset
$WidgYOff	Widget Y offset
$NeedsOptions	Needs Options
$DmgHungThirst	Damage from Hunger/Thirst
$HungerRate	Hunger Rate
$ThirstRate	Thirst Rate
$FatigueRate	Fatigue Rate
$SurvRespec	Survial Respec/ Restore
$RespecSkillPoints	Respec Skill Points
$RestSkillProg	Restore Skill Progress
$PointsToRestore	Points To Restore
$SkillPtsRestored	Skill points restored successfully.
$AreYouSureRefund	Are you sure you want to refund all earned Survival skill points so you can reallocate them?
$OptionIntended	This option is intended to be used to reclaim Survival skill progress that was lost due to a clean save or mod uninstallation. Do you wish to continue?
$SelectTotalNumber	Select the total number of skill points to restore. This will replace your current progress.
$ModStopping	Mod Stopping. Exit MCM menu and wait for mod to stop.
$ModStarting	Mod starting. MCM options will appear after closing the menu and letting the mod start.
$SHToggleModDesc	Enable or disable SunHelm.
$SHToggleFTDesc	Toggle Fast Travel on or off.
$SHToggleAnimsDesc	Enable/Disable playing animations when eating and drinking.
$SHToggleMsgDesc	Toggle messages that appear when your needs change.
$SHToggleTutsDesc	Toggle tutorials.
$SHToggleDamageDesc	Toggle damage from hunger/thirst.
$SHToggleRefillDesc	Enable/Disable refilling animations.
$SHWidgXOptionDesc	Set the X offset of the widget
$SHWidgYOptionDesc	Set the Y offset of the widget
$SHToggleRawDesc	Toggle damage from raw meat. Beast races and Wood elves are not effected.
$SHWereFatigueDesc	Toggle increased fatigue when exiting werewolf beast form.
$SHWerePauseDesc	Toggle pausing needs during beast form.
$SHVampireOptDesc	Set what needs vampires will deal with.
$SHVampireThirstDesc	Toggle vampire thirst progressing half as fast.
$SHCannibalDesc	Toggle ability to eat dead bodies as certain races.
$SHWerewolfFillDesc	Choose what needs feeding as a werewolf refills.
$SHToggleWidgDesc	Turn widgets on or off.
$SHHungerRateDesc	Set the rate that hunger increases.
$SHThirstRateDesc	Set the rate that thirst increases.
$SHFatigueRateDesc	Set the rate that fatigue increases.
$SHWidgetOrientDesc	Set orientation of widget.
$SHDisplayTypeDesc	Choose between alpha, color, or a hybrid of both.
$SHPresetDesc	Choose a preset widget location.
$SHToggleSoundsDesc	Toggle sound notifications from needs.
$SHSurvRespecDesc	Select to have all spent skill points refunded.
$SHSurvRestoreDesc	Select to restore lost skill point progress.
$SHToggleCWPenDesc	Toggle the carry weight penalty added by SunHelm.
$SHAlcoholNumDesc	Number of drinks required to become intoxicated.
$SHVisualEffects	Toggle visual effects when drunk or euphoric.
$SHToggleHungerDesc	Turn hunger off/on.
$SHToggleThirstDesc	Turn thirst off/on.
$SHToggleFatigueDesc	Turn fatigue off/on.
$NeedsHelp	Managing Needs
$NeedsHelpMessage	There are three needs that you will have to manage. Hunger, Thirst, and Fatigue. These needs will have various effects on your well being. Letting these needs get in bad shape too often will cause your well being to suffer. Keeping these needs well maintained will have a positive effect on your well being.
$RefillHelp	Refilling Bottles
$RefillHelpMessage	Empty bottles can be refilled in bodies of water. You can do this by activating an empty bottle in your inventory while standing in water, or buy using the refill power. Using the refill power in freshwater will cause your character to also take a drink. Refilling bottles in the ocean or other bodies of saltwater will give you bottles full of saltwater. You can take these bottles to a cooking station to distill these into fresh water for drinking.
$WerewolfHelp	Werewolf Needs
$WerewolfHelpMessage	In werewolf form, feeding as a werewolf can replenish food, thirst, or both depending on your settings. (Food and thirst is default). Werewolves in human form can eat raw food, and while in beast form, hunger, thirst and thirst do not increase. However, your fatigue will increase by a large amount after transforming back to a human.
$VampireHelp	Vampire Needs
$VampireHelpMessage	By default, feeding as a vampire will replenish thirst. If another needs option is chosen feeding will replenish thirst and fatigue. Feeding as a normal vampire, vampire lord, or even the vampire lord killmove where life is drained counts as feeding. Vampires also do not need to worry with well-being as long as mortal is not the chosen option. Blood potions also replenish the same as feeding would. As a vampire, your thirst increases more slowly than a normal living being.
$HungerHelp	Hunger
$HungerHelpMessage	Your hunger will need to be managed by eating food. Food is usually categorized into four categories. Heavy, medium, light, and soup foods. Heavy will restore more of your hunger than medium, and medium will restore more hunger than light. Soup happens to restore some of both hunger and thirst. Mismanaging your hunger will cause debuffs to be applied to your character the hungrier you become.
$ThirstHelp	Thirst
$ThirstHelpMessage	Your thirst can be managed by drinking water or soup. Water restores your thirst more than anything else, while alcohol and saltwater will actually increase your thirst. Mismanaging your thirst will cause debuffs to be applied to your character the thirstier you become.
$FatigueHelp	Fatigue
$FatigueHelpMessage	Your fatigue can be managed by sleeping for a few hours. Sleeping in a bedroll will only restore half as much fatigue as sleeping in a normal bed. Mismanaging your fatigue will cause debuffs to be applied to your character the more tired you become.
$EnableToView	Enable SunHelm to view this page.
$AlcoholNumber	Number of drinks
$DrunkSkoomaFx	Visual effects
$AlcoholSkoomaOptions	Alcohol and Skooma Options
$SHBoundHands	Cannot start with controls disabled.
$ArrowHelp	If enabled in the MCM, you will need to sleep to level up. Arrows will also have weight. These two features are tied to each other, so they cant be enabled/disabled seperately.
$ArrowWeight	Arrow Weight/Sleep level up
$ToggleHunger	Toggle Hunger
$ToggleThirst	Toggle Thirst
$ListsReset	The formlists have been reset
$AreYouSureReset	Are you sure you want to reset the formlists?
$SHResetDesc	Reset the food and drink formlists.
$ResetFormLists	Reset Food/Drink FormLists
$ToggleFatigue	Toggle Fatigue
$SHArrowWeighDesc	Toggle both arrow weight and sleep level up.
$PauseOblivion	Pause Oblivion Needs
$SHOblivionDesc	Toggle pausing needs in Oblivion or other immortal realms.
$WaterskinOptions	Waterskin Options
$WaterskinEquip	Toggle Waterskin Equip
$SHWaterskinInfo	Toggle equipping waterskin on player.
$WaterskinLocation	Waterskin Equip Location
$WaterskinLocationInfo	Choose where waterskin shows on the player's body.
$Back	Back
$Left	Left
$Right	Right
$ToggleFirst	Toggle First Person Notifications
$ToggleFirstInfo	Choose 1st or 3rd person notifications.
$ToggleBottle	Toggle bottle returns
$ToggleBottleInfo	Toggle getting bottles back when drinking beverages.
$ExitMenu	Please exit MCM and wait for system to start.
$Hotkeys	Hotkeys
$DrinkAndFillHk	Drink And Fill Hotkey
$DrinkAndFillHkInfo	Set a hotkey for for Drink and Fill. Hover over option and press "T" to unbind.
$ContinuanceHk	Continuance Hotkey
$ContinuanceHkInfo	Set a hotkey for Continuance. Hover over option and press "T" to unbind.
$ContinuanceOptions	Continuance Options
$TogglePowers	Enable/Disable Powers
$TogglePowersInfo	This option will remove the "Drink and Fill" and "Continuance" powers if you have them. If you do not have them, it will enable them again.
$PowersRemoved	"Drink and Fill" and "Continuance" have been removed.
$PowersAdded	"Drink and Fill" and "Continuance" have been added.
$DetailedCont	Toggle detailed Continuance messages
$ToggleDiseases	Toggle Overhauled Diseases